One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
You just never learn, do you?!
‫لا تتعلمين أبدًا، صحيح؟‬
Put me down! I'll pay later!
‫...اتركني، سأدفع لك لاحقًا‬
With my body!
‫بجسدي...‬
Not you, too!
‫!يا مغفلة‬
You made some more boys cry?
‫أأبكيتِ صبيانَ ثانيةً؟‬
They made me mad!
‫لأنهم أغضبوني‬
It's okay. Kids will be kids.
‫لا بأس فإن هذا مجرد شجار أطفال‬
They said your tangerines suck!
‫قالوا إنّ يوسفيّك سيئ‬
They said what?!
‫ماذا قلتم؟‬
Bell-mère!
‫!بيلمير‬
Don't give in to anyone...
‫لا تنحنيا أمام أيّ أحد‬
Even girls need to be tough...
‫حتى الفتيات عليهم أن يكنّ قويّات‬
It doesn't matter what people think!
‫لا تهتما إلّم يثني الناس عليكما‬
Don't resent the world you were born into...
‫ولا تبغضا العالم الذي وُلدتما فيه‬
And no matter what happens, don't forget how to smile.
‫ولا تنسيا أبدًا المقدرة على الابتسام في أيّ وقت‬
Live
‫سأعيش‬
– Bell-mère!
‫!بيلمير-سان‬
Under my rule, anyone who can't pay dies!
‫تحت حُكمي، من لا يدفع يموت‬
Got that, you worms?!
‫أفهمتم أيتها الديدان؟‬
What's this?
‫ما هذه؟‬
A sea chart?
‫خريطة بحرية؟‬
No!
‫!لا‬
I drew that! It's important to me!
‫!أنا من رسمتُها وهي قيَّمة بالنسبة لي‬
Give it back!
‫!أعدها‬
You drew this?
‫رسمتِها؟‬
Nami! No!
‫أحْجمي يا نامي‬
Oh?
‫،عجبًا‬
This ain't half bad.
‫أبهرني هذا حقًّا‬
We can use this brat! Grab her!
‫يمكننا استخدام هذه الشقية، أحضروها معنا‬
Right!
‫حاضر‬
No!
‫!لا‬
Lemme go! Lemme go! No!
‫!أفلتني، أفلتني! لا‬
Let Nami go! Let go!
‫!أفلِت نامي، أفتلها‬
Stop!
‫!مهلًا‬
You got your money!
‫حصلتَ على مالَك‬
You swore you wouldn't hurt her!
‫ووعدتَ ألاّ تمسّها بسوء‬
And I won't. I'm just borrowing her for a bit.
‫أجل، لن أمسّها بسوء بل سأستعيرها فحسب‬
Mr. Gen, help me!
‫النجدة يا غين-سان‬
Keep your hands off them!
‫أبعدوا أيديكم عن الطفلتين‬
Kuroobi.
‫كوروبي‬
Mr. Gen...!
‫غين-سان‬
Mr. Gen! Mr. Gen!
‫غين-سان، غين-سان‬
Don't worry... I'll save you, Nami...
‫لا تقلقي... سأُنقذكِ يا نامي‬
I won't let you through...
‫...لن أدعكم تمرّون‬
No! It's okay! You don't need to save me!
‫لا، لا بأس، لستَ بحاجةٍ لإنقاذي‬
Please!
‫أرجوك‬
Let's end this.
‫لننهِ الأمر‬
I'll... save–
‫...سأُنقذ‬
I don't want anyone else to die!
‫!لا أريد أن يموت أحدٌ آخر‬
They sank every last one of our ships...
‫أغرقوا جميع سفن القرية‬
Our plan to have Nojiko and Nami escape to sea...
‫...فكرتنا في نُهرّب نامي ونوجيكو عبر البحر‬
was far too optimistic.
‫كانت متفائلة جدًّا...‬
Just as I feared, the Marines won't help us.
‫وكما كنت أخشى فإن البحرية تأبى الإنصات لنا‬
This is his island, now.
‫إنها جزيرته الآن‬
Bell-mère knew exactly what would happen!
‫كانت بيلمير تعرف‬
She knew how pirates operate from her time in the Marines!
‫عرِفَت كيف يعملون تمامًا نظرًا لخبرتها مع البحرية‬
And she knew nobody was going to get away...
‫...كانت تعرف أنّ لا أحد بوسعه الهرب‬
They took Nami with them.
‫...أخذوا نامي معهم‬
What am I...
‫...ماذا‬
supposed to do now...
‫...يفترض بي فعله الآن‬
Bell-mère?
‫يا بيلمير-سان؟‬
We've found out where the Arlong Pirates are!
‫عرفنا مكان إقامة قراصنة أرلونغ‬
It seems they intend to settle down on this island!
‫يبدو أنهم ينوون الاستقرار في جزيرتنا هذه‬
It's time to decide!
‫حان الوقت لنقرر‬
Do we fight now, defiant to the end?!
‫أنقاتل الآن ونموت متحدّين لهم؟‬
Or do we bide our time, hoping the government comes to rescue us,
‫أم نضع آمالنا في انتظار المساعدة من الحكومة‬
while living under the executioner's axe?!
‫بينما نعيش مع خوفنا من أن نُقتل في أي وقت؟‬
It's one or the other!
‫!إما هذا أو ذاك‬
Only Marine Headquarters stands a chance against them.
‫لا غير مقر البحرية بوسعه مجابهتهم‬
But they have their hands full in the Grand Line.
‫لكنه منشغل تمامًا بالغراند لاين‬
The chances of them coming all the way out here are slim to none!
‫آمالنا بأن يأتوا حتى هنا لا طائل منها‬
And I can't abandon Nami!
‫لكن لا يُمكنني أن أترك نامي‬
I'll fight!
‫سأقاتل‬
I'll fight, too!
‫سأقاتل أيضًا‬
I can't just go on knowing I abandoned a child!
‫لا يمكنني عيش حياتي عالمًا أني تخلّيت عن طفلة‬
Everyone here is family!
‫جميعنا عائلة هنا‬
Even if I die fighting them, I'm gonna save Nami!
‫حتى إن متُّ خلال قتالي معهم فسأنقذ نا-تشان‬
Bell-mère gave her life to protect those kids!
‫ضحّت بيلمير بحياتها من أجل حمايتهما‬
This time, we'll give 'em hell!
‫فلنقاتلهم ثانيةً‬
If any one of us fights back, we'll all be blamed anyway!
‫سيُلقون اللوم علينا جميعًا على أي حال إن قاتل أحدنا‬
Nami!
‫!نامي‬
Hey, Nami!
‫!نا-تشان‬
Are you alright?!
‫هل أنتِ بخير؟‬
Nami! Nami!
‫!نامي، نامي‬
Are you okay? Are you hurt? Did they do anything to you?
‫أأنتِ بخير؟ أأُصبتِ بأذى؟ أفعلوا لكِ شيئًا؟‬
Nami?
‫نامي؟‬
I'm... joining...
‫...سأنضم‬
Huh?
‫ماذا؟‬
the Arlong Pirates...
‫...إلى قراصنة أرلونغ‬
to draw sea charts as their cartographer!
‫!لأرسم الخرائط البحرية بصفتي رسامتهم...‬
What are you saying, Nami?
‫ماذا تقولين يا نامي؟‬
Are you thinking straight?
‫أفقدتِ عقلكِ؟‬
Did they do something horrible to you?
‫فعلوا لك أمرًا مريعًا؟‬
They did, didn't they?
‫صحيح؟‬
No.
‫لا‬
They threatened you, right?!
‫هدَّدوكِ، صحيح؟‬
Tell us!
‫!لا‬
Let go of me!
‫!أخبرينا‬
Nami...!
‫...نامي‬
Nami!
‫!نامي‬
Th-That tattoo... Arlong's flag...!
‫...إ-إنه وشم أرلونغ‬
You...
‫...أنتِ‬
Nami...
‫...نامي‬
Check it out...
‫...انظروا إلى هذا‬
They gave me all this money...
‫...أعطوني مالًا كثيرًا‬
and they say they'll buy me whatever I want...
‫...وقالوا إنهم سيشترون لي كلّ ما أريد‬
Nami!
‫!نامي‬
Unforgivable! Despicable!
‫!لا يغتفر، لا يغتفر‬
Joining those guys is absolutely unforgivable!
‫!الانضمام لطاقم قراصنة لا يغتفر قطعًا‬
Not them! No way!
‫!ولتلك الجماعة خاصةً‬
Don't you know what kind of people they are?!
‫أتعرفين معدنهم؟‬
Who cares?!
‫وإن يكن؟‬
If following the rules gets me killed like Bell-mère,
‫،إن كان اتِّباعي القواعد ينهي بي المطاف ميتةً كبيلمير-سان‬
then I'd rather break them!
‫!فإنِّي أُفضِّل خرقها‬
I can't believe you...
‫...لا أصدق هذا‬
Bell-mère...
‫...بيلمير-سان‬
Bell-mère sacrificed her life to save us!
‫!بيلمير-سان قُتلت بسببنا‬
How can you just–
‫...كيف تسوِّل لكِ نفسكِ‬
That's enough, Nojiko.
‫يكفي يا نوجيكو‬
Leave, Nami!
‫غادري يا نامي‬
Never show your face in this village again!
‫إيّاكِ أن تطأي قدمًا في قريتنا هذه ثانيةً‬
Nami!
‫!نامي‬
How could she be so blind?
‫كيف لها أن تكون بهذا الطيش؟‬
Did she never see... Bell-mère as her mother?!
‫ألم تعدّ بيلمير أمًّا لها؟‬
No, that's not true...
‫...هذا ليس صحيحًا‬
Nami loved Bell-mère...
‫...أحبَّت نامي بيلمير-سان‬
Hey...
‫...بالمناسبة‬
Didn't Bell-mère say...
‫...ألم تقل بيلمير‬
that, if we survive...
‫...إنه إن نجونا‬
we'd be happy someday?
‫سنكون سعداء يومًا؟‬
She said we'd be so happy.
‫قالت إننا سنكون في غاية السعادة‬
Yeah.
‫نعم‬
After Arlong dragged me off,
‫،بعد أن سحبني أرلونغ معه‬
five Marine ships came to capture him.
‫أتت خمس سفن من البحرية للقبض عليه‬
He sank them like they were nothing.
‫لكنه أغرقها بكلّ سهولة‬
I don't think they'll send any more help.
‫لا أظنّ الحكومة سترسل مساعدةً ثانيةً‬
So I have to take matters into my own hands.
‫فأدركتُ أن عليَّ التصرف بنفسي‬
I made a deal with Arlong...
‫فعقدتُ اتفاقًا مع أرلونغ‬
to buy Cocoyashi Village.
‫لشراء قرية كوكوياشي منه‬
The whole village?
‫لشراء القرية؟‬
For 100 million berries.
‫مقابل مئة مليون بيري‬
Once I buy it, we'll all be free.
‫بمجرد شرائها، سنكون جميعًا أحرارًا‬
No one else will have to die.
‫ولن يموت أحدٌ آخر‬
In exchange, I have to join his crew and draw sea charts.
‫بالمقابل، عليّ انضمام طاقمهم لأرسم خرائط بحرية‬
One hundred million berries, though?!
‫لـ-لكن، مئة مليون بيري؟‬
How could anyone ever earn–
‫–كيف يُمكن لأحدٍ أن يكسب‬
I'll get that money!
‫!بل سأكسبه‬
No matter what it takes!
‫!مهما كلّف الأمر‬
Since everyone's working so hard to scrape together tribute, I'm on my own.
‫يكدح الجميع ليسدّدوا جزيتهم فإنَّ خياري الوحيد فعل هذا وحدي‬
If I ask anyone for help, more people will just get hurt.
‫فإن طلبتُ المساعدة من أحدٍ سيتأذى مزيدٌ من الناس‬
It's not gonna be easy, y'know...
‫...سيؤلمك هذا‬
I know.
‫...أعلم‬
Staying with the people who killed Bell-mère will hurt.
‫سيؤلمك البقاء مع قتلة بيلمير-سان‬
I'll be fine.
‫لا بأس‬
I'll put on a big smile, even when I look at him!
‫سأتصنّع ابتسامةً كبيرة عندما أرى وجهه‬
I've decided not to cry anymore.
‫قرّرتُ عدم البكاء أكثر‬
From here on out, I'll fight on my own!
‫قرّرتُ أن أُقاتل وحدي‬
Nami was only ten.
‫كانت نامي في سن العاشرة‬
Can you imagine how hard of a choice it was
‫أبوسعكم تخيل مدى صعوبة اختيارها القتال والبقاء حَيَّةً وحدها؟‬
For the sake of her village, she made that deal...
‫...عقدت صفقةً من أجل قريتها‬
She...
‫...إنها‬
I'll make those bastards pay for hurting–
‫...سأجعل أولئك الأوغاد يدفعون ثمن إيذائهم‬
Why... Big... Sister...?
‫لـ-لماذا يا أختي؟‬
I told you!
‫!كما أخبرتكم‬
I came here to tell you to stop!
‫!أتيت إلى هنا لإيقافكم‬
If you keep blabbing about being her friend,
‫،إن افتعلتم جلبةً تتعلق بكونها رفيقتكم‬
Arlong will get suspicious.
‫ستراود أرلونغ الشكوك‬
Her eight years of struggling will all be for nothing!
‫معاناتها ثماني سنين ستذهب هباءً منثورًا‬
She's already suffered enough.
‫عانت بما فيه الكفاية سلفًا‬
When you have to fight alone...
‫...عندما تضطر للقتال وحدك‬
nothing is more painful than people calling you friend!
‫لا شيء أكثر إيلامًا من أن يناديك الناس رفيقتهم‬
Get back here! Damn brat!
‫!عودي يا مغفلة‬
How dare you steal our treasure?!
‫كيف تجرئين على سرقة كنزنا؟‬
Stealing from pirates?!
‫تسرقين من القراصنة؟‬
Yeah!
‫نعم‬
These days, the sea is crawling with them! So I'm cashing in!
‫إنّي أستفيد من أعداد القراصنة الغفيرة في عصرنا هذا لصالحي‬
That's what they get!
‫هذا جزاؤهم‬
But you're all banged up!
‫لكنّكِ مكلّلة بالجراح‬
Yeah, I sorta screwed up. But check it out! One million berries!
‫!نعم، أخفقتُ نوعًا ما لكن انظري لهذا، مليون بيري‬
Who cares?! We need to hurry and treat those cuts!
‫انسي هذا، أنتِ بحاجة إلى عناية طبية عاجلة‬
I'm fine! It's nothing!
‫لا بأس، إنها ليست بالأمر الجلل‬
No one will ever find it here!
‫لن يجده أحدٌ هنا‬
I'll stash my money here, little by little,
‫،سأجمع المال شيئًا فشيئًا‬
and by the time it's full, I'll have 100 million!
‫وسأكون جمعتُ مئة مليون حينما أكبر‬
I have a long way to go...
‫ما زال الطريق طويلًا أمامي‬
One hundred million berries...
‫...مئة مليون بيري‬
It's taken a long time... but I'm just seven million away.
‫...استغرقت وقتًا طويلًا لكن بقيت سبعة ملايين فحسب‬
These days, I can score that much in one run!
‫بوسعي الآن كسب هذا القدر بمحاولة واحدة‬
Just...
‫...فقط‬
one more trip, and it'll finally be over...
‫...رحلة أخرى وسينتهي كل شيء‬
Everyone in Cocoyashi Village— and I—will be free of Arlong.
‫سأتحرّر أنا وجميع أهل قرية كوكوياشي من أرلونغ‬
And then...
‫...وأخيرًا‬
And then, I think...
‫...وأخيرًا حينها‬
I can finally smile from the bottom of my heart...
‫...سيصبح بوسعي الابتسام من أعماق قلبي‬
Bell-mère.
‫...بيلمير-سان‬
What business do the Marines have with Nami?
‫ما شأن البحرية مع نامي؟‬
No need to ask questions. Simply lead the way.
‫لا داعي لطرح الأسئلة، دلّني الطريق فحسب‬
Why does that guy have a pinwheel on his head?
‫لِمَ توجد مروحة على رأس ذلك العجوز؟‬
Awesome!
‫!مدهش‬
Guess I'll get cracking on my final heist!
‫!أظنني سأشرع في آخر نهبة‬
Mr. Gen?
‫غين-سان؟‬
And the Marines?
‫والبحرية؟‬
Are you the thief they call Nami?
‫أأنتِ اللصة المعروفة بنامي؟‬
We've received a tip that you've been hiding treasure stolen from pirates.
‫تفيد معلوماتنا بأنَّكِ خبأتِ الكنوز التي سرقتِها من القراصنة‬
And all plundered goods are government property.
‫فإن كل الغنائم التي نهبتها هي ملك للحكومة‬
I'll give you a warning.
‫سأوجه لك تحذيرًا‬
I'm an officer of the Arlong Pirates.
‫أنا ضابطة في قراصنة أرلونغ‬
Mess with me, and Arlong won't stand by quietly!
‫إن عبثتم معي‬
Silly girl.
‫ما أسخفكِ‬
Do you think you're dealing with me on equal footing?
‫أتظنّين أنّكِ في نفس مستواي؟‬
Find the stolen goods!
‫!اعثروا على المنهوبات‬
Wait!
‫على مهلكم‬
Don't you dare!
‫!توقفوا‬
Is this really what the Marines should be doing right now?!
‫أهذا ما يجب على البحرية فعله؟‬
The Arlong Pirates have murdered innocents and destroyed entire towns!
‫قتل قراصنة أرلونغ الناس وأبادوا بلداتٍ على بكرة أبيها‬
You know that!
‫إنكم تعرفون هذا‬
He rules this island with an iron fist, trampling lives into the dirt!
‫إنه يحكم هذه الجزيرة بضراوةٍ دائسًا على حياة الناس‬
Is that how the government works?!
‫أهكذا تعمل الحكومة؟‬
Busting petty thieves while turning a blind eye to all of this?!
‫تُطاردون لصوصًا صغارًا وتغضّون الطرف عن كل هذا؟‬
Watch how you speak to me.
‫لا تتحدثي بتعالٍ‬
Continue searching!
‫تابعوا بحثكم‬
For years now, the people of this island have been waiting for you to come help them!
‫إن جميع أهل هذه الجزيرة ينتظرون مساعدتكم منذ سنين‬
How can you just ignore them all for this?!
‫كيف تجرأتم على تجاهلهم من أجل هذا؟‬
Captain! This tangerine orchard seems suspicious!
‫!يبدو بستان اليوسفي هذا مشبوهًا أيها العقيد‬
Dig it up!
‫احفره‬
Keep your filthy hands off of Bell-mère's tangerine orchard!
‫أبعد يداك القذرتان عن بستان يوسفيّ بيلمير-سان‬
I won't let you take that money!
‫لن أدعكم تأخذون مالي‬
That money is... That money is...
‫...إنه مال... إنه مال‬
That money is the key to Cocoyashi Village's freedom!
‫!ذلك المال سبيل نيل قرية كوكوياشي حريتها‬
What gives you the right to take it away, Marine?!
‫!لا حق لكم في أخذه يا رجال البحرية‬
Oh?
‫ماذا؟‬
A backwater village sheriff, talking back to a Marine captain?
‫مأمور قرية متخلفة يرد على عقيد بحرية؟‬
Mr. Gen...
‫...غين-سان‬
How do you know about that?
‫كيف تعلم الأمر؟‬
I've always known, Nami.
‫طالما عرفتُ يا نامي‬
Back then, I couldn't believe how you behaved,
‫،لم أصدّق ما فعلته آنذاك‬
so I confronted Nojiko afterward.
‫لذا واجهت نوجيكو لاحقًا‬
Everyone in the village has known since then
‫عرف جميع أهل القرية حينها‬
that you stayed with the Arlong Pirates to save the village.
‫أنّكِ بقيتِ مع قراصنة أرلونغ لإنقاذ القرية‬
We only feigned ignorance.
‫لكننا ادّعينا جهلنا‬
We thought our hopes would keep you
‫ظننا أن آمالنا ستمنعك من الهرب من آرلونغ لو قررتِ ذلك يومًا‬
You can't be serious...
‫...لا يعقل‬
Whatever are you talking about?
‫عمّ تتحدث؟‬
You're saying all the villagers are thieves,
‫أتقصد أنَّ جميع أهل القرية لصوص وعلينا القبض عليهم؟‬
He's saying that each and every one of us is fighting just to survive!
‫بل يقصد أنَّ كل واحدٍ منا يجاهد ليعيش‬
But only because we can't rely on the government!
‫وهذا لأننا لا نستطيع الاعتماد على الحكومة‬
If you're not here to help us, then get the hell out of here!
‫إن كنتم لن تُنقذوا قريتنا فغادروا حالًا‬
Screw around and Arlong will sink your ship, too!
‫!اعبثوا هنا وسيهجم أرلونغ على سفينتكم أيضًا‬
Arlong, you say?
‫أرلونغ؟‬
I wouldn't be so sure...
‫...أشك في هذا‬
You still haven't found it?!
‫ألم تجدوه بعد؟‬
We're looking for 100 million berries here! Not a grain of rice!
‫!إننا نبحث عن مئة مليون بيري وليس حبة أرز‬
Hey, you!
‫أيها اللعين‬
How do you know how much there is?!
‫كيف تعلم مقدار الأموال؟‬
Oh, the 100 million?
‫أتقصد المئة مليون؟‬
Well, let's just call it a hunch.
‫ساورني حدسٌ فحسب‬
Don't tell me he...
‫...أيعقل‬
Don't tell me Arlong sent you here?!
‫أيعقل أن أرلونغ أرسلك إلى هنا؟‬
Who can say?
‫من يدري؟‬
We're simply dealing with theft as any civil servant would.
‫إنّنا نتعامل مع قضية سرقة كما يفعل أيّ موظفين حكوميين ببساطة‬
You damn government thugs!
‫!يا للحكومة البلطجية اللعينة‬
How could the Marines stoop to being pirate lackeys?!
‫كيف للبحرية أن تنحدر إلى درجة التبعية للقراصنة؟‬
Arlong!
‫!أرلونغ‬
I found it!
‫!وجدته‬
This is incredible!
‫!هذا مذهل‬
To think a girl like you could gather all of this!
‫...مذهلٌ أنَّ فتاة مثلك جمعت كل هذا الكم‬
It's all ragged and stained with blood...
‫...إنه ممزق وملطخ بالدماء‬
No matter! Money is money!
‫لا يهم، يظل المال مالًا‬
And thirty percent of it is all mine!
‫ومن نصيبي ثلاثون في المئة منه‬
Don't touch that...
‫...لا تلمسوه‬
Don't touch that... Don't touch that...
‫...لا تلمسوه... لا تلمسوه‬
Nami...!
‫...نامي‬
Don't touch that!
‫!لا تلمسوه‬
Nami...!
‫!نامي‬
Nojiko?!
‫!نوجيكو‬
Doctor! Doctor!
‫!أيها الطبيب، أيها الطبيب‬
What is it, Mr. Gen?!
‫ماذا هناك يا غين-سان؟‬
Nojiko's been shot!
‫!تعرضت نوجيكو لطلقٍ ناري‬
By who?!
‫ممّن؟‬
The Marines!
‫!البحرية‬
The Marines?
‫البحرية؟‬
Nami...
‫...نامي‬
Hey, Nami!
‫أهلًا يا نامي‬
What's up? Need help with anything?
‫ما الأخبار؟ أتحتاجين مساعدة؟‬
You're still here?!
‫أما زلت هنا؟‬
This has nothing to do with you! Just leave the damn island already!
‫!لا علاقة لكم بالموضوع، غادروا الجزيرة فورًا‬
Arlong!
‫!أرلونغ‬
You really want me to free your village that badly?
‫أتودين مني تحرير قريتكم إلى هذه الدرجة؟‬
Gather up 100 million berries and bring it to me.
‫اجمعي مئة مليون بيري وأحضريها لي‬
If you do that, I'll let you and the village go.
‫إن فعلتِ ذلك فسأخلي سبيلكِ أنتِ والقرية‬
Arlong!
‫!أرلونغ‬
When it comes to money, I'd rather die than break a promise.
‫أفضّل الموت على خرق اتفاق أموال‬
I don't care how long it takes.
‫لا يهمني كم سيأخذ منك الأمر‬
I'm a fishman of my word.
‫سأفي باتفاقنا‬
Arlong!
‫!أرلونغ‬
Man, what's her deal?
‫ما مشكلتها؟‬
Oh?
‫!أهلًا‬
Why the long face, my capable cartographer?
‫ما الخطب يا رسامتنا الماهرة؟‬
What's with the scowl?
‫ما بالكِ عابسة؟‬
Those Marines you've been paying off stole all my money!
‫رجال البحرية الذين كنتَ ترشوهم سرقوا كل أموالي‬
I thought when it came to money, you'd rather die than break a promise!
‫ماذا عن قولك إنك تفضّل الموت على خرق اتفاق أموال؟‬
Why?!
‫لماذا؟‬
And when exactly did I break our promise?
‫متى خرقتُ اتفاقنا؟‬
Don't give me that! Those Marines of yours–
‫...لا تتغابَ، تواطأت مع البحرية من أجل‬
Let's hear it!
‫!أخبريني‬
Damn you...
‫سحقًا لك‬
Damn you! Damn you!
‫سحقًا لك، سحقًا لك‬
Ah, I get it now!
‫،فهمت‬
So your money's been stolen?
‫سُرق مالكِ إذًا؟‬
That's a damn shame.
‫يا للأسف‬
But, hey. A deal's a deal.
‫لكن الاتفاق يبقى اتفاقًا‬
If you can't bring me 100 million berries,
‫،إلّم تحضري لي مئة مليون بيري‬
I'm afraid I can't return your village.
‫أخشى أنني لا أستطيع إعادة القرية لكِ‬
You scumbag!
‫!أيها الحثالة‬
Hey, it's only 100 million berries!
‫ما هي إلّا مئة مليون بيري‬
Just start saving up again!
‫ابدئي بجمعها ثانيةً‬
Or maybe you're thinking of running away?
‫أم أنكِ ستهربين مني؟‬
Just remember, if you do, I'll kill everyone in Cocoyashi Village.
‫لكن إن هربتِ، فسأقتل جميع أهالي قرية كوكوياشي‬
Nami...
‫...نامي‬
We only feigned ignorance.
‫لكننا ادّعينا جهلنا‬
We thought our hopes would keep you
‫ظننا أن آمالنا ستمنعك من الهرب من آرلونغ لو قررتِ ذلك يومًا‬
Oh?
‫عجبًا‬
Running after all, huh?
‫أستهربين أخيرًا؟‬
Shouldn't we chase her down?
‫ألا يجب أن نلاحقها؟‬
Chase? What for?
‫نلاحقها؟ لماذا؟‬
She won't run away.
‫لن تهرب‬
She could never abandon the lives of the villagers.
‫ما كانت لتتخلى أبدًا عن أهل قريتها‬
You certainly do know how to play dirty...
‫...تجيد اللعب بدناءة حقًّا‬
As if I'd let a cartographer of Nami's caliber just leave.
‫وكأنني سأدع رسامة خرائط بمستوى نامي ترحل ببساطة‬
But I'm not completely heartless.
‫لكنني لستُ شيطانًا بلا قلب‬
I'll let her go, alright... after she charts every sea in the world!
‫سأمنحها حريتها فور أن تُنهي رسم جميع بحار العالم‬
That'll take decades!
‫!أي بعد عشرات السنين‬
You couldn't do that in a hundred years!
‫!ولا حتى مئة سنة ستكفي‬
Enough is enough! Arm yourselves!
‫!اكتفينا من هذا، تسلّحوا‬
We'll fight!
‫!فلنقاتل‬
Mr. Gen! Everyone! Please don't do anything stupid!
‫!يا غين-سان والجميع، لا تتسرعوا رجاءً‬
You can't die! It'll all be over!
‫!لا يُمكنكم أن تموتوا، سينتهي كل شيء‬
You have to survive, or it was all for nothing!
‫!عليكم أن تنجوا وإلّا سينتهي كل شيء‬
Eight years ago...
‫...قبل ثماني سنين‬
we swore not to throw away our lives!
‫أقسمنا ألا نهدر حياتنا‬
No matter how demeaning their rule was,
‫مهما كان حكمهم لنا مؤلمًا ومذلًا‬
we swore we'd endure it patiently as long as Nami kept on smiling!
‫أقسمنا أن نقاتل بصبرنا ما دامت نامي مبتهجة‬
But this is their answer!
‫لكن هذا كان جوابهم‬
Now that our village's only chance for freedom is gone, there's no hope left!
‫!بعد أن اندثرت فرصة قريتنا الوحيدة في نيل الحرية لم يعد هنالك أيّ أمل‬
Above all else,
‫،والأكثر من ذلك‬
we have to make those fishmen pay for toying with that girl's heart!
‫علينا أن نجعل أولئك البرمائيين يدفعون ثمن تلاعبهم بقلب تلك الفتاة‬
Sound good?!
‫أمِن اعتراض؟‬
Of course! Let's go!
‫!طبعًا لا، هيا بنا‬
For the past eight years, we've always been ready to fight!
‫كنا على أهبة الاستعداد للقتال دائمًا‬
I'll be damned if I spend another day under their rule!
‫!أرفض أن أدعهم يحكمونني ولو ليومٍ أكثر‬
Wait, everyone!
‫!تمهّلوا جميعًا‬
Nami!
‫!نامي‬
Just a little more!
‫!قليلًا فحسب‬
Just wait a little more!
‫!انتظروا قليلًا فحسب‬
I'll work hard again!
‫!سأعمل بجدٍّ ثانيةً‬
I'll save up the money again!
‫!سأجمع مالًا مجددًا‬
It'll be easy this time!
‫!سيكون الأمر سهلًا هذه المرة‬
I'm used to it! It'll be okay! There's nothing to worry about!
‫اعتدتُ على الأمر فسأكون بخير، لا داعي للقلق أبدًا‬
This is nothing compared to back then!
‫هذا لا يُعدُّ شيئًا مقارنة بآنذاك‬
I don't want anyone else to die!
‫!لا أريد أن يموت أحدٌ آخر‬
Everyone!
‫!جميعًا‬
I'm fine, really! I'll be okay!
‫!أنا بخير، بخير حال‬
That's enough.
‫هذا يكفي‬
Even you must know it's over.
‫تعرفين أن الأمر انتهى‬
You've been so brave, bearing the burden of the entire village for all these years...
‫...قاتلتِ ببسالة حاملةً حياتنا على عاتقكِ طوال هذه السنين‬
Joining them must have hurt more
‫...لا بُدَّ أنَّ انضمامكِ إليهم كان أشد ألمًا‬
than being stabbed through the heart.
‫من طعنةٍ في القلب...‬
You've done so well.
‫قاتلتِ ببسالة‬
Mr. Gen...
‫...غين-سان‬
Leave the village now.
‫غادري القرية‬
Mr. Gen?!
‫غين-سان؟‬
Do it, Nami.
‫افعليها يا نامي‬
Wh-What?!
‫مـ-ماذا؟‬
Nami, sweetheart...
‫...نا-تشان‬
Nami...
‫...نامي‬
You have a dream, and you know how to take care of yourself.
‫أنتِ فطنة وطموحة‬
Nojiko! Everyone!
‫!نوجيكو والجميع‬
I won't let you go!
‫!لن أدعكم‬
Stop it, everyone!
‫!توقفوا جميعًا‬
I can't watch anyone else get hurt!
‫!ليس بوسعي رؤية أحدٍ آخر يتأذى‬
They'll kill you!
‫!ستموتون‬
We know.
‫نعلم‬
It's no use! We've made up our minds!
‫!لا فائدة، حسمنا أمرنا‬
Get out of our way, Nami!
‫!تنحّي عن طريقنا يا نامي‬
Let's go, everyone!
‫!هيا بنا جميعًا‬
Even if we can't win, we'll give 'em hell!
‫حتى وإن لم نستطع الفوز فسنذيقهم الجحيم‬
Arlong...!
‫!أرلونغ‬
Arlong! Arlong!
‫!أرلونغ، أرلونغ‬
Ar–
‫...أر‬
Luffy...
‫...لوفي‬
What do you want?
‫ماذا تريد؟‬
You don't know anything.
‫لستَ عالمًا بشيء أصلًا‬
You have no idea what's been going on here for the past eight years!
‫لستَ عالمًا حتى بما حدث في هذه الجزيرة قبل ثماني سنين‬
No, I don't.
‫أجل، لا علم لي‬
This has nothing to do with you!
‫لا علاقة لك بالموضوع‬
I already told you to get off this damn island!
‫ألم أخبرك أن تغادروا الجزيرة فورًا؟‬
Yeah, you did.
‫أجل، أخبرتني‬
Then, leave!
‫!غادروا‬
I don't need you!
‫!لستُ بحاجة لكم‬
Get lost! Go! Leave!
‫!غادروا، غادروا‬
Go away!
‫!غادروا‬
Beat it! Get the hell out of here! Go!
‫!غادروا، غادروا، غادروا‬
Luffy...
‫...لوفي‬
Help me...
‫...ساعدني‬
Of course I will!
‫!أكيد‬
Hands off my treasure!
‫!لا تلمس كنزي‬
Luffy...
‫...لوفي‬
Let's go.
‫لننطلق‬
Right!
‫!أجل‬
Hey!
‫!أنتما‬
Are you guys alright?!
‫هل أنتما بخير؟‬
Did Arlong do this to you?!
‫هل أرلونغ من فعل بكما هذا؟‬
Move aside.
‫تنحيا‬
We have business with the fishmen.
‫لدينا ما نسوّيه مع البرمائيين‬
When we found out the truth about Big Sis Nami,
‫حين علمنا حقيقة أختنا الكبيرة نامي‬
we felt like all we could do was try to take down Arlong.
‫شعرنا أنّ الأمر الوحيد الذي بوسعنا فعله هو هزيمة أرلونغ‬
So we challenged him...
‫فتحديناه‬
...but we lost by a hair.
‫لكننا خسرنا بسهولة‬
Sorry, but we can't let you pass! You guys don't stand a chance!
‫اعذروني لكن لن ندعكم تدخلون، لا فرصة لكم للانتصار‬
What?!
‫ماذا؟‬
We're waiting for a certain crew to show up, you see!
‫إننا ننتظر مجيء رجالٍ معيّنين‬
A certain crew?
‫رجال معيّنين؟‬
I'd bet my life on it.
‫أُراهن بحياتي‬
They will come!
‫أنّهم سيأتون‬
– It's them!
‫ها هم أولاء‬
Outta the way!
‫تنحوا‬
Hey, do you think those two clowns were part of Zoro's crew?
‫يا جماعة، أتظنّون أنّ ذلكما الغبيين كانا من جماعة زورو؟‬
Zoro's? They seemed too weak for that.
‫زورو؟ أراهما ضعيفين جدًا على ذلك‬
They're not even worth killing.
‫لا يستحقّان القتل حتى‬
You got that right!
‫!فعلًا‬
What the hell?!
‫!ماذا؟‬
Which one of you is Arlong?!
‫أيُّكم أرلونغ؟‬